"Move over a little, I'm going to sit in here. Kyon~~"
「ちょっと詰めて～！」って 座って来るの　あれ　キュン！
Right. Right. I understand why girls do that
それ　すっげ～分かる　あれでしょ。
They even do something to their foot and thighs
太ももとか　ピシっと くっつけて来るやつでしょ？
At first, I was like, "what are you doing?"
最初は　「何なんだよ？」と 思うんだけど→
But, deep down inside I'm happy when they do that. Do you understand what I mean?
ちょっと嬉しいみたいな 分かるでしょ？
But for me, I fancy girls who jumps lively. What?
俺はね　派手に　コケてほしいの。 何？　それ。
I know that girls are prim and proper
あのね　いつもは　しっかりしてる 女のコが→
I fancy girl who shouts "Ah!" and then she falls down flat on the ground
突然　「あっ！」つって ベチャって　コケんの。
And then she will stand up and see her say "Teehee~"
で　こう　立ち上がる時に 「エヘっ」みたいな。
I really don't understand at all Why?
うん　全然　分かんない。 何で？
Why? Why? Why? What?
何で？　何で？　何で？ 何？　それ。
I know you understand at that time that it happened. Why is it that you don't understand right now?
お前の時　分かってやったのに 何で俺ん時　それ？
Falls flat on the ground? Yup. I don't understand. Why?
ベチャでしょ？ うん。 うん　分かんない。 何で？
Just wait... Just like this feeling. Just like this
ちょ…　待って もう　こんな感じ　こんな感じ。
Ok ok..yeah
はいはい…　うん。
Am I fickle minded?
＜こういうの 浮気っていうんだろうか？＞
I like Kyuto but,
＜Ｑ１０が好きなのに→
I know that there is a woman who is human meant for me.
人間の女のコに　ちょっと ときめいたりする自分がいる＞
Move over a little Here..
（詩織）　ちょっと詰めて！ （宙）　よいしょ。
Girls are kind of scary
＜女のコは　少し怖い＞
But, they are cute, moving constantly,
＜でも　何か　かわいくて ひっきりなしに動いてて→
and lively..
生き生きしてて…＞
What are you looking at?
何だよ？
Here I go! Ready!
（文子）　行くよ！　せ～の　えい！
Girl playing catchball~
女子とキャッチボールか～。
Let's do that.
（Ｑ１０）　やりますかな？
Yea..just as I thought
うん…　やっぱね。
Kyuto-san that is not how..
Ｑ１０さん あの　こういうんじゃなくて→
W...wait...
もうちょっと　こう…。 わ～い　わ～い！
This is fun~!
楽しいな～！
whoa~
わ～い！ うぉっ!?
This is fun.. This is not fun you idiot!
楽しい　楽し… 楽しくねえよ　バカ！
Wow~~ Stop!
わ～い　わ～い！ やめて！　すいません！　あっ！
What do you like to do next?
ハァ…。 次は何をしたいですかな？
Eh? Enough already.
えっ…？　もういい。
Aa! Sorry. Sorry I'm sorry
おぉ！　ごめん　ごめん。 あっ　すいません。
Are you ok?
そっちこそ　大丈夫？
Why does her skin becomes red?
何で肌が赤くなるのかな？
She's embarrassed. Skin becomes red when you're embarrassed
恥ずかしいんだよ はにかんで　赤くなるの。
Her embarrassment shows up to her face
はにかみ顔も　ポイント高いな。
Kyuto is embarrassed!
Ｑ１０　はにかみます！
Oh! You can do it? Watch carefully.
おぉ！　できんの？ やって見せてください。
Aa.. Therefore...
あぁ　だから…。
I want to see something like "Nooo~~"
「ヤダ～　アハっ」みたいな。
Noooooo..aaaa....uuuuu...
ヤダ　ア　ア　ア　ア　ウ　ウ…。
u! You're not embarrassed at all!
ウ！ 全然　はにかんでないし。
Kyuto is embarrassed! Kyuto is embarrassed! Stop doing that!
はにかみマックス！ わわわ…！　ダメ　ダメ！
What are you saying? You startled me!
何いってんの？　ビックリした。
Do you want me to give you a break right now?
今ので勘弁してくれますか？
What? Give me break?
何？　勘弁って。
From now on, please think of me as embarrassed.
これからは　これが　はにかみだと 思ってください。
That is embarrassment? Puff.
それが　はにかんでんの？ パフ。
I see. I understand. From now on, you are embarrassed. Jeez
はい　分かりました　じゃあ これからは　それが　はにかみね。
That feeling was not a lie
＜あの気持に　ウソはない＞
((Between human life and a robot, which is more important?))
（中尾）((深井は　人間の命とロボットと どっちが大事なんだよ？))
((Kyuto))
((Ｑ１０だ))
I know it wasn't a lie but
＜ウソは　ないのに→
what is this messed up feeling?
何だろう　このモヤモヤは…＞
I see.. You're embarrassed. I get it. So, you can stop doing that.
そっか　はにかんでんだな 分かった　もういいから。
Rather than being with a girlfriend, this is like accompanying a child
これじゃ　恋人っていうより 子連れじゃん。
Where was the place that I got
＜どこに　しまえばいいんだろう→
this messed up feeling...
このモヤモヤを…＞
As the world is singing a song today, There is someone out there who is thinking of you.
（ラジオ）　歌は世につれ　世は歌につれ 今日も　どこかで　あなたを思う。
Through songs, you can convey feelings that you can't show
（ラジオ）　歌が伝える　いえない気持。
Today also, just for you, let's sing together "Saraba Koibito" song ("saraba koibito": Goodbye sweetheart)
さぁ　今日も　あなたのために 歌いましょう　『さらば恋人』。
♪~ I wrote a farewell letter~~
（ラジオ）♪～　さよならと　書いた手紙 （小川　訪）　ファ～。
Huh? Where are you going? Alumni Homecoming!
あれ？　どこ行くの？ ♪～ （小川しげ）　同窓会！
Candies... OK! Handkerchief~~
（しげ）　アメちゃん　ＯＫ！ ♪～ よそ行き用ハンカチ　あ～る！
Ticket. Alright!
切符　よ～し！
♪~ We were always that happy~~
♪～　いつも幸せすぎたのに
♪~ But the two of us was not aware of it~
♪～　気づかない二人だった
♪~ chachachachachan~
♪～　チャチャチャチャチャン
Seems like you are having so much fun. You think that I am weird right?
そんなに楽しいもんかね？ ハマグチ君　どうなってんのかしらね？
You are getting old
そら　ヨボヨボでしょうよ。
I'm counting on you. Ok. Ok. I know. Go.
留守　頼んだわよ。 はいはい　分かったから行きなよ。
Goodbye!
ごきげんよう！
I want to travel forever
ハァ～… もう　永遠に旅しててほしい。
Hot pot? My mom went out
（柳）　鍋？ おふくろが出かけちゃって。
Somehow, it's boring eating alone
何か　１人で飯食うの　おっくうで。
Sure Huh?! Really?
（柳）　いいですよ。 えっ!?　ホントに？
Then, let's go shopping together before going home
じゃあ一緒に　帰りに買い物でも。
You even want to do that...
いや　そんなことまで…。
haa~~ Oh...
ハァ～。 あっ…。
I'm sorry You're in a middle of difficult work
すいません 難しい　お仕事の最中に。
I'll go back..
じゃ　帰りに…。
Shall I tighten the rice or the noodle?
締めは　ご飯にするべきか 麺にするべきか？
It has been so long since the last time I ate rice at home
久しぶりだな～　家で　ご飯。
For the choir competition, do you have a song in mind that you want to sing?
（早苗）　合唱コンクールで 歌いたいものありますか？
Anything will do
（鷲田） 別に何でもいいよ　そんなの。
"Anything will do" is not what I wanted to hear
（明日香）　「何でもいい」とかいうと 余計　決まんないよ。
Something suitable. Something suitable. ♪～ Both of us were non aware
（伊坂）　適当でいいよ　適当で。 ♪～　気づかない二人だった
Sensei, can you suggest something good?
（良枝） 先生は何がいいと思いますか？
I think cod hot pot is better
俺　やっぱ　タラ鍋かな。
Well. What is it? Come on decide quickly!
いや　何だよ　早く決めろよ！
Sensei, what is the song that you just sang? "Taraba Koibito" ("Taraba": cod)
（唯）　先生が歌ってたの　何？ タラば恋人。
"Taraba koibito"? No, that's not it..
（宮沢）　「タラば恋人」？ いや　そうじゃなくて　あの→
Farewell. "Saraba Koibito"
「さらば」　『さらば恋人』。
Isn't that good? That one, "taraba"
（由起恵）　それでいいんじゃないの その　「タラば」で。
Well then, who among you thinks that "taraba koibito" is good?
（早苗）　じゃあ 「タラば恋人」でいいと思う人？
Me~ W...wait. Oi!
（生徒達）　は～い。 ちょちょ…　こら！
Come on. Stop this! Sensei, are you going to eat cod hot pot today?
お前ら　いいかげんにしろよ！ （栗林）　先生　今日　タラ鍋ですか？
Yes. I'm gonna eat that one
うん　そうなの。
Huh!
（影山）　うわっ！
We are not in good terms right now
（影山）　今　ヤバイんだって俺達。
I thought she understands
別れようと思ってんだよね。
Kawai!? Shhh!
河合と!? シッ！
How am I going to tell her?
もう　どういったらいいの？　ねぇ。
I don't want to hurt her~
傷つけたくないんだよな～。
It's impossible to tell her now! Absolutely impossible!
わっ！　今は無理　絶対無理！
You do understand
（月子）　深井君のとこも 気をつけないと→
that if you are not careful, it will break right?
別れることになっちゃうかもね。
Huh?
はぁ？
Try using this
（月子）　これ　使ってみたら？
Hold this up to the forehead of Kyuto
（月子） 久戸の　おでこに　かざすと→
and your wish will be granted
深井君の望みが叶うよ。
Pitch
ピッて。
Wait a minute! That is disposable
ちょっと待てよ！ それ　使い捨てだから。
Ha?
はぁ？
Is that you Runa-chan..
おぉ？　ルナちゃん職人の…！
aaa! That's good then!
あぁ！　ちょうどよかった！
I will give this to you
あの　これ　もらってくれないかな。
Hmm?
ん？
I see~ You shoplift
（中尾）　そっか～　万引したのか。
You're not angry?
（藤丘勇人）　怒らないの？
I'm not in the position to get mad at you
俺は　ひとをどうのこうの　いえる 立場じゃないからね。
I even did something horrible to someone
とっても悪いことをした 人間なのさ。
((If you don't give her to me, I am going to jump from here!))
（中尾）((くれないんだったら こっから飛び降りてやる!!))
There's always a limit to human's desire
人間の欲望っていうのはね 切りがなくてね。
I became obvious when I am fixated into something
そいつに取りつかれると 周りが見えなくなってしまう。
I mean, I thought it is ok to become obvious
っていうか　周りが どうでもよくなってしまう。
That is..
それは…→
really the worst
最悪だ。
No one is here
いないのか。
Im sorry but...can you sit down there for a while?
あの　ちょっと　ごめん ここ　座ってくんない？
whoa!
おぉ！
Heita
平太。
Ne~~ Where are we going from now?
ねぇ　今から　どこ行く？
I am good to go anywhere
私は　どこでもいいよ。
To your favorite place
平太の好きな所で。
W...wait!
ちょ…　ちょっと待って！
What's the problem?
どうしたの？
Kyuto?
Ｑ１０？
Call me Karen
花恋って呼んで。
K...Karen-san
か…　花恋さん。
By the way,
そうだ→
shall we kiss?
キスしよっか？
No..I'm ok. Come on, let's kiss.
いいです！ いいじゃん　キスしようよ。
No. No need to do that!
いいです！　いいですって！
What's wrong with you?
何なんだよ。
Kyuto?
Ｑ１０？
What is happening here!
何なんだよ　これ！
Kyuto? Oi!
Ｑ１０　おい。
Hey Kyuto! Kyuto!
Ｑ１０　おい！　Ｑ１０！
She will be fine. Charging is cut off
大丈夫　充電が切れただけだから。
Only half of electric power is used
それ　電力　ハンパなく使うのよ。
I'll give this to you.
（月子）　あげる。
What kind of person are you?
何者なんだよ？
It's much better if you don't know
（月子）　知らないほうが いいんじゃない？
It'll be complicated once you know
知ると　ややこしいよ～。
By the way, do not talk about me to any person
そうだ 私のこと　ひとに　いわないでね。
If you do,
いうと→
I'll withdraw Kyuto from you
Ｑ１０は　即撤収だから。
For what reason?
何のために？
Kyuto came here for what reason?
Ｑ１０は 何のために　ここに来たんだ？
I told you
だから→
It's better if you don't know
知らないほうが　いいんだって。
Store manager.
（警備員）　店長。
Your elder brother? Yea
おにいさん？ うん。
W..why are you here? Well..
（藤丘　誠）　な…　何で？ いや　あの…。
Just a mere acquaintance..
ちょっとした知り合いで…。
You embarrassed me! I'm not going to forgive you!
恥かかせんじゃねえよ！ 情けねえよ！
You'll never be an adult if you do that!
そんなことしてると ろくな大人になんねえぞ！
I am very sorry for what happened!
すいませんでした！
I wonder if I can do something
僕　何かになれるかな？
Eh?
え？
When I grow up, I will not be poor right?
大人になったら 貧乏じゃなくなる？
So that mom and dad will come back home
お父さん　お母さん 家に帰って来るようになる？
Just like the old days, where all of us go to a family restaurant
（勇人）　昔みたいに みんなでファミレス行ける？
Can I even ask for a strawberry pancake?
イチゴのパンケーキ 頼めるようになる？
Don't get mad. I'm not angry.
（勇人）　怒らないでよ。 （藤丘）　怒ってねえよ。
It's ok. You don't have to force yourself.
もういいよ　無理しなくて。
I'm going to buy you your pancake!
お前にパンケーキぐらい 食わせられるよ！
Eh?
え？
Hey! Somebody out there! Hello!
お～い！　誰か～！ もしも～し。
Hey!
（中尾）　お～い！ （藤丘）　もしも～し。
Enough already.
もういいじゃん。
You can stop that
もういいよ。
If I die like this, nobody will get sad anyway.
このまま死んでも 誰も悲しまないって。
It's a good thing that this happened first
この先 いいことなんて　ないし。
What are you talking about?
何いってんだよ。
That good thing
あった？　いいこと。
Up until now, are you happy living with me?
お兄ちゃん　幸せだった？
Ah~~ the rhythm of kitchen knife is still different
あ～　やっぱり 包丁のリズムが違うもんな。
ton ton ton ton...
トントントン…って。
That sound is refreshing
若いんだよな　音が。
I'm home~~
（しげ）　≪ただいま～≫
Ah~~ I'm so tired. Eh? Aa! Why are you here?
あ～　くたびれた。 え？　あっ！　どうしたの？
I'm really stupid! I mistook a wrong date!
私　バカだよね　間違えた　日にち。
Eh?! Well...Don't say that. Try checking again one more time.
え～!?　いやいや　そんなことない もう一回　ちゃんと調べてみたら。
What is this? We're going to eat hot pot today?
何？　今日　鍋？
Did you make this? I'm not the one making..
あんた　やったの？ 僕ってわけじゃないんだけど。
Sorry for interrupting~
お邪魔～しました。
W...wait Where are you going?
いや　ちょ…　ちょっと どこ行くの？
Whatever~
あぁ～　もういいよ ほっとこう　もう。
Sorry about that. Let's eat. Let's eat
ごめんなさいね 食べましょう　食べましょう　ね。
I can't let her go like that! Eh?
そういうわけに　いきませんよ。 え？　だって　あの…。
Eh?!
えぇ～!?
♪~ Both of us is not aware
（しげ）♪～　気づかない二人だった
♪~ chachachachachan
♪～　チャチャチャチャチャン
I saw that. I'm sorry.
何か　すねちゃったみたいで ごめんなさいね。
Please take good care of my son.
息子を　よろしくお願いします。
Well, I am not good for him..
あ…　いや　ダメですよ　私なんか。
Why do you say that?
どうして？
Well.. However I think of it, I am not worth it...
いや　だって　ダメですよ どう考えたって　私みたいな…。
Just as I thought, my son won't do.
やっぱり　あの子じゃ無理ですか。
I also think of that.
ハハハ！　そりゃそうだわね。
Well...that's not what I mean..
いや　そうじゃなくて…。
I am only thinking of myself as how am I going to live
私は　自分のことしか考えないで 生きて来た人間ですから。
For the two of us..
お２人みたいな→
I'm not capable of giving
ちゃんとしたお家に 入れてもらえるような→
a decent home, properly. Properly?
人間じゃないんです。 ちゃんとなんて…　フフフ。
Ogawa-sensei is like a crushed shop that is now growing..
小川先生を育てて お店もつぶさずに　やって来た。
able to sacrifice something of his own...
自分の　やりたいことを 犠牲にして…。
I am unable to do it.
私には　できないことです。
We're the same. That's because it's who you are
同じですよ あなただって　そうでしょ？
Up until now, have you heard of a place
今のとこに来るまでには→
where someone was able to sacrifice a lot of things?
いろんなものを犠牲にして 来られたんじゃないですか？
We're the same
同じですよ。
Choose something that you like.
好きなものを選んで来た。
Because of that, in the end, you can say "because I am here"
その果てに 私ら　ここにいるんですから。
You're right.
はい。
Cool wind is blowing~
（生徒達の声） ♪～　冷たい風にふかれて
I'm going to a town alone at dawn~
♪～　夜明けの町を　一人行く
I am the bad guy~
♪～　悪いのは　僕のほうさ
You are not the one~
♪～　　君じゃ　ない
Shaking from the window of the train~
♪～　ゆれてる汽車の窓から
At that time, houses became so small~
♪～　小さく家が　見えたとき
Without knowing, I cried heavily in my heart~
♪～　思わず胸にさけんだ
I will be back for sure~
♪～　必ず帰って来るよと
We were always that happy~
♪～　いつも幸せすぎたのに
But both of us were not aware of it~
♪～　気づかない二人だった
chachachachachan~
♪～　チャチャチャチャチャン
There's a map that guides me how to go back home~
♪～　ふるさとへ帰る地図は
I'll probably throw it into the sea of tears~
♪～　涙の海に捨てていこう
I am the bad guy here~
（藤丘） ♪～　悪いのは　僕のほうさ
You are not the one~
♪～　君じゃ　ない
Oh. Eh?
あっ。 （恵美子）　え？
Sorry
あっ　ごめん。
That song awhile ago, is just a random song that we're going to sing right?
さっきの歌 やたらに染みちゃってさ。
Because we're eventually following it.
だって　その通りなんだもん。
I was so happy that I was unaware of it.
幸せ過ぎて 気づかなかったんだよね　私。
I think so too.
俺も　染みた。
And that part, "I am the bad guy, You are not the one"
「悪いのは　僕のほうさ 君じゃ　ない」ってとこ。
Fujioka-kun thinks like an adult
藤丘君って　大人だね。
That's Nakao-kun and Fujioka-kun
（民子）　あっ　中尾君と藤丘君だ。
I really want to watch something like this.
何か見たことあるなと 思ったんだよね。
Huh? You want to watch something like that?
（民子）　えっ 見せたいものって　これ？
It's boring right?
あぁ…　つまんなかったね。
Not really
別にいいけど。
Oh..you're going back home? Yup. I'll go home
あっ　もう帰る？ （民子）　うん　帰るね。
≪ Tatsuya wait! ≫ Kya!
≪タツヤ～！≫ キャっ！
Ouch~ That hurts~~
（民子）　痛った。
Are you in pain or something? Eh?
気分悪いの？ え？
Well...I'm okay. I'm ok. But...
あぁ　いや　大丈夫　大丈夫。 いや　でも…。
Ah! It's now time for my IV
あ～　そうだ　俺　点滴の時間だ。
But you have IV right now Eh?
点滴　今やってるじゃん。 え？
Y..yeah you're right...
あぁ…　いや　そうなんだけどね…。
Ano...
あの…。
Eh?
え？
Kubo-kun, sorry for the wait~~
（看護師）　久保君　お待たせ～。
Hmm? What's the problem?
ん？　何よ？
No..nothing.
いや　何でもないです。
It seems like something is wrong with me.
（久保） 俺　どうかしちゃったみたい。
What are you talking about?
何だよ。
I am afraid to die
死ぬのが怖い。
I'm really scared of death
死ぬの　ものすごい怖い。
Weird right?
変だろ？
I'm weird
変なんだよ　俺。
You're not weird
変じゃ　ないよ。
Me too. I always think what will happen to me tomorrow.
俺だって　明日どうなってんだろう って思うよ。
I have been thinking of that up until now
そんなこと　今まで 考えたこともなかったのにさ。
In other words, I'll go out with Kubo-kun?
（民子）　それは　つまり 久保君と付き合えってこと？
Umm...that's not what I mean.
あぁ…　じゃなくて。
Then what is it? I don't understand what you're saying.
じゃ　何？　訳分かんない。
Sorry sorry. What I mean is..
ごめん　ごめん　つまり→
Tell him that he must live longer. Ha?
長生きしてやってほしいんだ。 は？
Ever since Kubo met you
あいつ　山本と会ってから→
He's been saying "I'm afraid to die"
「死ぬのが怖い」って言い出して。
Although he says "I'm scared" I know he doesn't really mean it.
どんな検査も　「怖い」とか 絶対いう奴じゃなくて。
But then, why "I'm afraid to die" all of a sudden...
なのに 「自分が死ぬのが怖い」って…。
Yamamoto is scared of dying?
「山本が死ぬのが怖い」って。
If that's the case, I can't imagine it..
「想像したら どうにかなりそうだ」って…。
If..
「もし→
the most important person to you is suddenly gone..
大切な人が 急に　いなくなってしまったら→
I dunno what am I going to do.
自分は どうなっちゃうんだろう」って。
Somehow, I want to tell him not to say something like that.
何かしてほしいって話じゃ ないんだ。
Just live longer each day.
一日でも長くいてほしい。
Just like that.
うん…　それだけなんだ。
((Shall we kiss?))
((キスしよっか))
♪~ ((chachachachachan))
♪～((チャチャチャチャチャン))
Hey.
ねぇ。
Where are you from Kyuto?
Ｑ１０は　どっから来たの？
I don't have a memory about it.
そのメモリーは　ありません。
What about you? Where do you come from?
平太は　どこから来たのですか？
Eh?
え？
I don't remember also.
あぁ　いや　俺も記憶にない。
I see.
そっか　そうだよな。
We don't know anything much about it.
いつ　いなくなんのか 分かんないんだよな　俺達。
Let's go.
行こう。
Oh! Sorry for the wait.
（岸本）　おう　お待たせ　お待たせ。
Sorry about that.
あの　これ　すみませんでした。
Right now, I'm getting used to liking it.
あぁ　これ 今　結構　気に入ってんだよね。
Look at the texture. It feels good when touching it.
ほら　柄みたいでさ いい感じじゃない　ヘヘ。
I've been thinking of starting to work during daytime.
俺　昼間の仕事　始めようと思って。
I see.
そっか。
So does that mean, you're not coming to school anymore?
それじゃあ　学校　来れなくなるな。
Yes
はい。
I don't like this.
嫌だ　嫌だ！
I'm the principal here. Yet I can't do anything.
校長なんて　名前ばっかりで 何にも　できねえんだもんな。
♪~ Cool wind blowing
（生徒達の声） ♪～　冷たい風にふかれて
♪~ Going to a town alone at dawn
♪～　夜明けの町を　一人行く
♪~ I'm the bad guy here
♪～　悪いのは　僕のほうさ
♪~ You're not the one
♪～　君じゃ　ない
Fujioka-kun has quit school
（大友）　藤丘が学校やめたらしい。
What do you mean quit? So, he's not coming anymore?
（森永）　「やめた」って…。 もう来ないってこと？
Why is that? Well, we don't
何で？ （西村）　まぁ　俺達には→
know his reasons right?
分からないことが あるんじゃないの？
We don't know
そんな別れ方　ないよ。
Suddenly quitting without saying anything to us...
突然　何にもいわずに 行っちゃうなんて…。
But that is something that can't be helped, right?
でも　しょうがないんじゃない？
Probably because of family matters.
だって　家の事情とか あるだろうし。
But, can't we do something about it? You're right
でも　何かあったんじゃないの？ （鷲田）　だよな。
He can't receive his diploma
（鷲田）　卒業証書 もらえないんだぜ　なのに→
Does this normally happen?
来てたんだぜ　普通　来るか？
Why did he quit?
それを　やめるなんてさ。
Nakao-kun, do you know something?
中尾君 何か知ってるんじゃないの？
Huh? Me?
わ…　私ですか？
Eh? Why Nakao-kun knows something?
え？　何で中尾なの？
There's a video site where Nakao-kun and Fujioka-kun appeared
（民子）　動画サイトに 藤丘君と中尾君が映ってた。
You were inside the elevator that stuck, right?
エレベーターに 閉じ込められてたよね？
You're right, but...
それは　そうなんですけど…。
What do you mean the elevator stuck?
「閉じ込められてた」って どういうこと？
What happened? What happened inside the elevator?
何があったの？ （理花）　エレベーターで　何かあったの？
F...Fujioka's younger brother shoplifted...
ふ…　藤丘の弟が　万引して→
Fujioka got mad to his younger brother...
藤丘が怒って　そしたら弟が…。
((When I grow up, I will not be poor right?))
((大人になったら 貧乏じゃなくなる？))
Fujioka said "I'm going to buy you your pancake"...
（中尾の声）　藤丘　「パンケーキぐらい お前に食わせられるよ」って→
So, we went to a restaurant and rode the elevator..
それで　レストランのある ビルのエレベーター　乗って…。
Eh? Hey! Hey! Hello! Hello!
((え？　お～い　お～い！)) ((もしも～し　もしも～し！))
Enough already
((もういいじゃん))
You can stop now
（勇人）((もういいよ))
It's a good thing that this has happened
((この先 いいことなんて　ないし))
What are you talking about!
((何いってんだよ！))
That one. It's good thing
（勇人）((あった？　いいこと))
Up until now, are you happy that you're living with me?
((今まで生きてて お兄ちゃん　幸せだった？))
I am
((あったよ))
Since the day you were born
((お前が生まれた日))
At that time,
((あの日→
it snowed
雪が降った))
I got a call from dad..
((お父さんから電話があって→
He said "you have a younger brother that is born"
「生まれたのは　弟だよ」って))
I was thinking..
((俺…))
when you grow up, we can play snowball fight together
((大きくなったら 雪合戦できるなって思った))
Don't say enough already
((「もういい」とか　いうなよ))
We still have to play snowball fight together!
((俺　まだ お前と雪合戦してねえじゃん))
When we get out of here...
((ここ出たらさ…))
We still have a lot things to do together
((まだ　してないこと 全部やろう))
It's possible that we can do everything right?
（滝）　俺達ってさ 何も　できねえんだよな？
Now, let's continue the practice and then let's go home
さぁ　ちゃっちゃと練習して 帰ろうぜ。
Then, let's try again memorizing "Saraba Koibito" in our heads
じゃあ　『さらば恋人』 もう一回　頭から。
Farewell Fujioka...
（五條）　「さらば藤丘」か…。
As the world is singing a song.
歌は世につれ　世は歌につれ。
Somebody is thinking of you somewhere
今日も　どこかで　あなたを思う。
Through songs, you can convey feelings that we can't show
歌が伝える　いえない気持→
Let's sing together for the sake of Fujioka!
さぁ　今日も藤丘のために 歌いましょう！
For the sake of Fujioka?
「藤丘のため」って。
To deliver our innermost feelings!
みんなの心を届けるだよ。
How are we going to do that?
どうやって…。
What about we sing in front of Fujioka-kun's house?
ねぇ 藤丘君の家の前で歌うとか。
I think somebody will get angry. I don't want to be caught by the police
それ　怒られるんじゃない？ （西村）　絶対　警察　呼ばれるよな。
That's probably right. But..
まぁ　そうだよね。 いや　でも→
I understand that feeling
気持は　分かる。
What will happen if the heart of everyone
伝えられなかった　みんなの心は→
is not properly conveyed?
どうなるのですか？
What is it really that we wanted to say...
私達が　いいたかった 「さよなら」は→
Is it "Goodbye. Where are you going?"
どこに行くのですか？
Alright! There it is!
よし　来た！
This is your fortune. This is my fortune
（民子）　こっちが久保君ので こっちが私の。
This is nice.
（久保）　いいじゃん　２人とも。 私ね→
You probably think that I'm stubborn
久保君が思ってる以上に しぶとい女なんだよ。
Really?
そうなんだ…。
I will definitely survive
絶対に　しぶとく生き抜く。
Of course, suddenly appearing in front of you. I'll never go away.
突然　久保君の前から 消えたりなんかしない。
I promise you that.
約束する。
I'm just saying
それだけだから。
Hayato, go take a bath Ok
勇人　風呂入る。 はい。
♪~ ≪I wrote a goodbye letter≫
♪～　≪さよならと　書いた手紙≫
♪~ ≪I placed it on the table≫
♪～　≪テーブルの上に置いたよ≫
Onichan!
お兄ちゃん！
♪~ ≪I see your sleeping face≫
♪～　≪あなたの眠る顔みて≫
♪~ ≪I went out quietly≫
♪～　≪黙って外へ　飛びだした≫
♪~ We are always happy
♪～　いつも幸せすぎたのに
♪~ But the two of us were non aware
♪～　気づかない二人だった
♪~ chachachachachan
♪～　チャチャチャチャチャン
♪~ The cool air is blowing
♪～　冷たい風にふかれて
♪~ And I'm going to town alone at dawn
♪～　夜明けの町を　一人行く
♪~ I'm the bad guy here
♪～　悪いのは　僕のほうさ
♪~ You are not the one
♪～　君じゃ　ない
♪~ shaking from the window train
♪～　ゆれてる汽車の窓から
Shut up! I'm going to call the police!
うるせぇぞ！ 警察　呼ぶわよ！
They are singing loudly outside someone's house It's troublesome
家の外で　大声で歌ってて 困ってるんです。
♪~ I cried heavily in my chest
♪～　思わず胸にさけんだ
♪~ I'll come back for sure
♪～　必ず帰って来るよと
♪~ We are always that happy
♪～　いつも幸せすぎたのに
♪~ But the two of us were non aware
♪～　気づかない二人だった
I'm really very sorry. Be careful...
（岸本）　申し訳ございません 気をつけます…。
Don't let them do such things again..
二度と このようなことがないように→
Guide them properly.
くれぐれも　ご指導のほう よろしくお願いしますよ。
Is everyone gathered around here?
みんな　回ったか？
Why is it that all of you are depressed?
何だよ　これぐらいのことで しょげんなよ。
It can't be helped.
しょうがないよ 常識　破んなきゃ→
There are certain things that we can't convey
伝わらないことだって あるんだから。
Hmm? You were glad that you were able to do it?
ん？　やんなかったほうが よかったか？
Well, I'm glad that I did it.
（西村） いや　やってよかったと思うよ。
Fujioka looked happy though
藤丘　嬉しそうだったしな。
But, when I saw sensei apologizing to the cops..
（佐野）　でも 先生が謝ってんの見たら…。
It's ok. It doesn't matter how many times I bow down my head
いいじゃないの　頭下げるぐらい。
It is my job to bow down my head anyway
頭下げんのは　俺の仕事。
I was used to be called as "Kishimoto pecker"
「ペコリーノ岸本」って 呼ばれてたんだよ　ヘヘヘ…。
Now, now, drink it!
ささっ　飲め！
Let's drink quietly. Let's drink quietly though~
静か～に飲みましょう　静か～に。
In cue, you will drink it
キュキュっと ス～っと飲みましょう。
Goodbye
（岸本）　さよなら。 ≪さよなら≫
≪Thank you ≫ This time, it's goodbye~
≪ありがとうございました≫ （岸本）　どうも～　さよなら。
≪ goodbye ≫
≪さよなら≫
Fujioka-kun is strong willed right?
（恵美子）　藤丘君って強いよね。
As compared to me, I don't have the guts to do that
それに比べて 私って何なんだろうなぁって。
You're not the only one thinking like that...
自分のことしか考えてない…。
Shall we break-up?
別れよっか。
I have always known it before
ずっと前から分かってたんだ。
The best way for us is ...
２人にとって　一番いい方法は→
saying goodbye.
さよならすることだって。
That's what you been thinking right?
影山君も　そう思ってたでしょ？
I want to properly see the truth...
ホントのことを ちゃんと見ることが→
This what you call, painful reality
こんなに辛いって思わなかった。
This is like drama right?
ハハ…　何か　ドラマみたいだね。
Just like the drama, I'm going to say it properly...
ドラマみたいに ちゃんと　いえるかな？　私…。
Goodbye.
さよなら。
I'm home
ただいま。
Eh? What's this?
えっ　何？
You came back at a wrong timing
（深井武広） お前　悪い時　帰って来たな。
What's going on? Oh! You came back
どうしたの？ （深井ほなみ）　帰って来たの。
That's great. I'm going to start in a while.
ちょうどよかった じゃあ　今から始めるね。
Come here. What's going on?
（武広）　ほら。 何なの？
What is she doing?
何？　これ…。
Japanese dance. Hah?
日本舞踊。 えっ？
I heard that next Sunday, there is a concert.
（深井千秋）　今度の日曜 発表会があるんだって。
Rehearsal
リハーサル。
This is...This something that a family member should not see
いや　これ 家族で見んのキツイでしょ。
She's stubborn Just bear with it.
キツイよ。 忍従だよ　忍従。
sigh~ That hurts...
ハァ～。 痛たた…。
What is she aiming for? We have no choice..
何を目指してるんだろうね あの人。 しょうがないよ→
She said she wants do it since she was young. So, I just have to bear with it.
若い時　やりたいこと 我慢して来たんだから。
She just randomly wanted to do what the adolescents are doing nowadays.
手当たり次第に　やってみたい 年頃なんじゃないの？
By the way, mom cried a long time ago right?
そういや　母ちゃん 昔　よく泣いてたよな。
Really?
（武広）　そう？
((Don't! Don't cry! Don't do it!))
((ダメ！　泣いたってダメ！ やるの！))
((It's not good doing that!))
((やらなきゃダメ！))
((You will be ok))
（看護師）((大丈夫だからね))
I was really angry that time. And I said to myself I'll surely go to the toilet
（深井の声） 俺のこと　すっごい怒った後さ 必ず　トイレ入るんだよ。
I will definitely cry inside
絶対　泣いてたんだと思うよ。
I want to take back the minutes that you cried
泣いた分　取り返したいんだよ。
Just accompany me ok? Ok? ok?
付き合ってあげよ？ なっ？　なっ？
Part 2 will now begin
第２部が始まります。
Eh?
（武広）　えっ？
No way! There's a part 2?
ウソ～！ ２部もあるって。
I don't know! I really don't know...
知らないよ　俺　知らない…。
I don't need anything that is coming from you
自分の思い通りになるものなんて いらない。
Don't overdo it
無理しちゃって。
I think it's not about overdoing it
無理すんのも いいんじゃないかな。
Then, do you know everything about Kyuto?
Ｑ１０のことなら 何でも知ってる？
Of course
もちろん。
Even her embarrassed face?
じゃあ　はにかんだ顔も？
Q10 is built within an artificial muscle
Ｑ１０が内蔵してる 人工筋肉では→
Regarding her complicated facial expression, I can't answer you that
そこまで複雑な表情には 応えきれない。
Kyuto has an embarrassed face
Ｑ１０は　はにかんだ顔するよ。
That is why, I'm telling you she isn't your belonging
だからって あんたのものじゃないからね。
Q10 ...
Ｑ１０は→
belongs to us
私達のものなんだからね。
Kyuto?
Ｑ１０？
Kyuto
Ｑ１０。
It's a rainbow! A beautiful rainbow appeared!
虹です わ～い　虹が出ています。
Let's look at it together
一緒に見ましょう。
Is there something you wanted to say to me?
私に　してほしいことは ありますか？
Eh? Well, even if I say something...
え？　いや　…っていわれてもな。
Aa...I hope that...
あぁ　俺が望むのは…→
Kyuto will not cry in the future
Ｑ１０が　この先 泣いたりしないことかな。
Puff
パフ。
Please turn your head to the other side
向こうを向いててください。
Here it is!
はいよ！
Hmm?
ん？
These are my tears.
私の涙です。
These are tears?
えっ　これ涙なの？
From now on,I'm not going to cry anymore
これで　私は　もう泣きません。
You'll not cry forever?
いや　だって… 一生　泣かないってこと？
Forever.
一生です。 うん？
Hm...I wonder what robot's life is... 250 years later
ロボットの一生って？ あと２５０年。
You'll not cry? For 250 years?
泣かないの？　２５０年間。
What will you do if you cry?
泣きたくなったら　どうすんの？
I'll just remember Heita
平太のことを　思い出します。
Whenever I remember Heita,
平太のことを思い出して→
I will smile instead
代わりに笑います。
What are you thinking?
何か？
I'm embarrassed when you say that
いや　そんなこといわれて 恥ずかしかったんだよ。
Please let me see an embarrassed face
では　はにかんでください。 フフフ…。
Kyuto is embarrassed.
Ｑ１０　はにかみます。
Don't you think the sky is also embarrassed?
空も　はにかんでいるのですか？
Puff
パフ。
After the tears are drawn out,
＜涙を抜いた後→
I somehow feel that Kyuto was
Ｑ１０の　どこかに→
able to fill up the emptiness inside me.
ポッカリ出来た 空洞のことを思った＞
These tears as the evidence...
＜俺と出会った証拠として→
that I'll see 250 years later...
この先　２５０年間→
Kyuto is still able to live though
Ｑ１０は　その空洞を抱えて 生きて行く＞
I want to enter a cave that is less crowded...
＜ポッカリ空いた空洞は→
not completely filled up as time passes by
いつまで経っても　満たされない＞
But, she is
＜だけど　それは→
a proof that there is an important person
大切な人がいた証拠だ＞
Alright! Tomorrow I'll do my best for mankind!
よっしゃ 明日も人類のために頑張るぞ！
There is a proof that we have to continue living for that special someone
＜大切な人のために 生きた証拠だ＞
I thought I'm satisfied with everything...
＜すべてが 満たされていたと思っていた→
Just like in childhood...
子供時代には→
I don't know if I'll able to go back before...
もう 戻れないのかもしれないけど…＞
I'm fine the way I am
＜俺は　それでいい＞
You poor thing...
かわいそうだけど…。
I have no choice...
しょうがないよね。
I have met Kyuto
＜Ｑ１０と出会った＞
That is all that matters
＜それで　いい＞